A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, National Affairs, Office Files of Esther Roditti Schachter FA655
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, National Affairs, Office Files of Esther Roditti Schachter
1971-1977
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA655
1.2 Cubic Feet
Conditions Governing Access note
Material is open for scholarly research, with prior archival review.
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Separated Materials
Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.
Ford Foundation
- Pre-Ford Report, I
  - Some Criteria for Evaluating State and Local Air Pollution Control Laws, 1971 (Box 1)
- Subject Files, II
  - Bakke Conference, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Children -- General, 1973-1975 (Box 1)
  - Children --Luncheon Meetings, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Civil Rights, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Corrections, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - Court Administration (Coyne), 1973 (Box 1)
  - Ellis Paper, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Environment, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - International Division Committee on Women, 1977 (Box 1)
  - International Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Juvenile Delinquency, 1975-1977 (Box 1)
  - McKay, Robert -- Equality Through Litigation, Jan 1976 (Box 1)
  - National Youth Alternatives, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Organized Crime, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Public Interest Law Committee, 1975-1977 (Box 1)
  - Public Policy and Social Organization Committee, 1977 (Box 1)
- Appendix A: Reports, 1975
  - Thennes, Mark and the National Youth Alternative Project; The Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act, Jun 30, 1975 (Report #019851)